Guide to the Cased Image File 1840-ongoing PR 12
© 2011 New-York Historical Society
- Series III: Tintype, 3
  - 11 Unidentified Young Females (11 Individual Images) (Item 3-419)
    2 Images of seated young females leaning on armrests, both wearing earrings, one wears a feathered hat; 3 images of vignettes of young girls, one wears a leaf in her hair and a brooch, two wearing light colored dresses with striped edging; 3 full length i
  - William Parker Butler (Item 3-420)
    Boy sitting on tasseled chair with face turned toward right, possibly at 8 or 10 years of age, dressed in vest and jacket with cap on lab.
  - Unidentified Female Brinkerhoff-McNulty Family Member or Friend (Item 3-421)
    Female figure seated, wearing white collar, long string of beads, right elbow resting on back of tasseled chair.
  - Sue Ellis (Mrs. John Hewston Jr.) (Item 3-422)
    Female figure, profile, wearing black lace mantilla, white collar, dark dress, earrings.
  - Mrs. James William Gowdey (Item 3-423)
    Female figure, standing with right hand resting on adjacent Adirondack table with flowering plant, wearing long black dress with white cuffs, hair parted in middle with bun in back, pendant with chain pinned to dress, chain around neck, earrings.
  - Malcolm MacMartin and Dr. Dan Stimson (Item 3-424)
    Two male figures seated, high hat in lap of male with moustache and goatee, both men wearing gloves and dark suits, male on left has moustache and is leaning right arm on tasseled armrest between sitters.
  - Elizabeth B. Ferris Terpeny, ca. 1863/00/00 (Item 3-425)
    Female figure, front view, wearing white bonnet with ties at neck, dark dress with ruffled sleeves, hair parted in middle.
    Accompanying note describes sitter's history,
  - Unidentified Male Lady Washington Engine Company No. 1 of Morrisania Member (Item 3-426)
    Male figure, front view, wearing black jacket and bow-tie, white shirt and black vest with badge, large moustache and hair parted on side.
  - Unidentified Male Lady Washington Engine Company No. 1 of Morrisania Member (Item 3-427)
    Male figure with large moustache, hair parted on side, wearing white shirt, black coat, vest, looking to left of camera.
  - Unidentified Male Eginton Family Member or Friend, 1872/00/00 (Item 3-428)
    Male figure, front view, seated, looking off to right of camera, wearing pinstripe pants and dark jacket and vest, white shirt, striped bow-tie, rounded hat with band, holding can in his left hand across lap, curly hair, backdrop, his left arm resting on
    Date inscribed verso.
  - Unidentified Male Eginton Family Member or Friend (Item 3-429)
    Male figure, front view, wearing dark coat and vest, light colored pants, white shirt, seated with his left arm resting on cloth covered armrest, hair parted on side, clean shaven.
  - Unidentified Male Eginton Family Member or Friend (Item 3-430)
    Male figure, front view, looking off to right of camera, seated on tasseled chair, his right arm resting on armrest, wearing striped necktie with white shirt, black jacket buttoned and black pants, hair parted on side, clean shaven.
  - Gabriel Hoyt, 1876/00/00 ca. (Item 3-431)
    Silhouette of male figure with moustache, hair parted on side, freckles, wearing black jacket with vest buttoned to top, white patterned tie with white shirt, 1/4 profile.
  - 13 Unidentified Couples (13 Individual Images) (Item 3-432)
    Young boy standing next to young girl seated in chair, girl wearing bonnet and striped stockings, wood floors; two young girls seated on log, tree backdrop; male seated and female standing wearing checked skirt and holding purse, cinched waist with belt a
  - 34 Unidentified Females (34 Individual Images) (Item 3-433)
    Female figures in various poses, 6 at 3/4 length with females leaning on tables or with their hands on laps, one holds a fur muff and has a fur collar with a feathered hat, one has braided hair, and one wears a pin on her hat; 6 are full length, with fema
  - James P. Harper Jr. (Item 3-434)
    Male figure seated wearing light colored coat, pocket watch on chain, patterned bow-tie, white shirt, britches and stockings, black hat, smiling, legs crossed, another figure mostly out of frame to his left, part of a larger image.
    A similar image of the same sitter is in the Cased Images File.
  - James P. Harper Jr. (Item 3-435)
    Male figure seated wearing light colored coat, pocket watch on chain, patterned bow-tie, white shirt, britches and stockings, black hat, legs crossed, part of a larger image.
  - Unidentified Female MacMartin or MacLaren Family Member or Friend (Item 3-436)
    Female figure, 1/4 profile view, wearing black dress with white cuffs and elaborate collar, brooch with chain, earrings, ring, arms crossed and resting on armrest in front of sitter, leaning forward slightly, hair in curls on top of head.
  - Charles Kirk (Item 3-437)
    Male figure, front view, looking off to left of camera, wearing chain and badge on vest, dark jacket with black collar, white shirt and dark bow-tie, beard and moustache, hair parted on side, hands on lap.
    Lady Washington Engine Company No. 1 of Morrisania Member
  - Unidentified Male Lady Washington Engine Company No. 1 of Morrisania Member (Item 3-438)
    Male figure, front view, wearing white shirt, light colored bow-tie, black jacket with badge and chain on vest, hair parted on side, moustache, hands on lap.
  - Unidentified Male Lady Washington Engine Company No. 1 of Morrisania Member (Item 3-439)
    Male figure, front view, looking to left of camera, wearing black jacket and unbuttoned vest, white shirt and light colored bow-tie, hair parted on side.
  - Unidentified Male Lady Washington Engine Company No. 1 of Morrisania Member (Item 3-440)
    Male figure, front view, moustache, wearing gold chain and badge on black vest, gold pin and chain on lapel, black jacket and light colored bow-tie, white shirt with 2 gold buttons, looking off to left of camera, hands on his lap.
  - Unidentified Male Lady Washington Engine Company No. 1 of Morrisania Member (Item 3-441)
    Male figure, front view, wearing black vest with chain and badge, white shirt with 2 gold buttons, bow-tie under collar, black jacket, moustache.
  - Unidentified Male Lady Washington Engine Company No. 1 of Morrisania Member (Item 3-442)
    Male figure, front view, wearing dark jacket with black collar, white shirt, light colored bow-tie, vest buttoned with chain and badge, moustache and sideburns.
  - Miss Arnold and Aunt Libbie, MacMartin or MacLaren Family Members or Friends (Item 3-443)
    Two female figures seated in grass with white picket fence in background, female with light dress holding hat on lap, front view, female in darker dress with checked shawl on lap, hat hanging on fence.
  - James P. Harper Jr. (Item 3-444)
    Male figure seated on rock, wearing britches and dark stockings, ankles crossed, parasol at feet, cane partially out of frame, wearing hat and light colored sweater, trees in background, probably part of a group portrait.
  - Unidentified Male Lady Washington Engine Company No. 1 of Morrisania Member (Item 3-445)
    Male figure, front view, wearing necktie with chain, white shirt, black jacket and vest, hair parted on side, looking to left of camera.
  - Unidentified Female and Relyea Family Member or Friend (Item 3-446)
    Female figure wearing dark coat with white bow at collar, earrings, hat.
  - Richard Damm (Item 3-447)
    Male figure, front view, looking 1/4 profile off to left of camera, wearing chain on black vest, top button open, wearing black coat, bow-tie, white shirt, moustache and beard, light colored hair.
  - Unidentified Male Lady Washington Engine Company No. 1 of Morrisania Member (Item 3-448)
    Male figure looking off to left of camera, wearing badge on black vest, chain, black jacket and bow-tie, goatee and moustache, half length.
  - Friedrich Pinkel (Item 3-449)
    Male figure, seated, in uniform of Civil War soldier (north) holding sword in left hand, clean shaven, coat unbuttoned in middle, back drop of United States flag and military tents.
    Sitter is son of Friedrich and Juliana (Loos) Pinkel of New York City, and is shown here in his uniform of the 13th New York Battery, 1861-1863, commanded by Capt. Julius Dieckmann; donor is niece of sitter.
  - Unidentified Female [Broadbent & Phillips] (Item 3-450)
    Female figure wearing dark dress with bow at collar, necklace with locket, earrings, flower and bow in hair, looking off to right of camera.
  - Unidentified Male Webb Family Member or Friend (Item 3-451)
    Male figure, nearly full-length, wearing hat and standing with arms crossed over chest, long beard, moustache, long black coat (to knees), light gray pants.
  - John Cambell with 8 Unidentified Cambell Family Members (Item 3-452)
    Group of eight figures: two females are seated in front at either end, one male is seated in middle alongside a young girl who is standing, two male and two female figures are standing in rear; Cambell is second from right in back row.
    Enclosed note reads: "John Campbell second from right back row with family of Fonda NY where my mother was born. He is my maternal grandfather, was born at Glen Lyon Perthsi[?] Highlands Buried at Perth[?]."
  - Unidentified Male Gilder Family Member or Friend (Item 3-453)
    Male figure seated with white hair, wearing dark jacket with white shirt and black bow tie, hands on lap.
  - 2 Unidentified Female MacMartin or MacLaren Family Members or Friends (Item 3-454)
    Two female figures, one seated, one standing, tree and fence in background, seated female wearing black dress, gray shawl, standing female wearing gray cloak with light dress and striped trim, both wearing hats and bows at necks.
  - Mead Residence, 1870/00/00 ca. (Item 3-455)
    Drawing room, Victorian furnishings, chandelier in foreground has two layers of globes, side table at right with two candelabra on it, arm chair next to it, arched entrance at other end of room.
  - Mead Residence and self-portrait, 1870/00/00 ca. (Item 3-456)
    Chandelier in foreground with two layers of gloves, wall mirror in decorated Victorian frame extending from almost the ceiling to near the floor, the mirror reflects a male figure (photographer) with box camera on a tripod, also reflects chandelier, chair
  - 2 Unidentified Females (Item 3-457)
    Two female figures, female on left standing wearing black cape with dark skirt, white ties from bonnet in bow at neck, white sleeves, flowers in bonnet, female on right seated wearing polka dot dress, checked shawl around shoulders, hair parted in middle
  - Capt. Northup and His Rookies (Item 3-458)
    Group of Civil War soldiers, Grand Army of the Republic, total of 28 men standing at "Parade Rest", two men in officers uniform in front rant holding swords, all others holding muskets, tents in background and two men perched in tree.
  - 3 Unidentified Males, 1880/09/09 (Item 3-459)
    Male figure seated far left wearing moustache and beard, checked jacket and vest, dark pants, black shoes, hair parted on side, seated with his right leg crossed over left thigh, male figure standing center wearing black jacket buttoned to top, white coll
    Mat inscribed "Glasgow Sep 9/80".
  - Julia Raymond? (or Mrs. Raymond) (Item 3-460)
    Young female figure standing, full length, front view, wearing short black skirt and stockings, black cap, sweater and plaid scarf, hands in pockets of skirt, smiling.
  - Unidentified Male [C.G. Hill's Ferrotype and Photographic Gallery] (Item 3-461)
    Male figure, front view, wearing white collar, dark bow-tie, black vest and jacket, his left arm on armrest, hair parted on side, 1/2 length.
    With photographer's name and location: "Pictures enlarged to any size, and colored in Water, Oil, and India Ink."
  - Eugene A. Livingston [Baxter, W.H.], 1869/04/00 (Item 3-462)
    Male figure, profile view, half length, partial silhouette, wearing black coat buttoned to top, white collar, moustache, hair parted on side, left arm on tasseled armrest.
  - Unidentified Male Servant of A.B. Smith (Item 3-463)
    Male figure, front view, wearing black jacket and pants with white shirt and black necktie, holding tall cane or walking stick, standing, clean-shaven, fence and tree in background, plants and grass in foreground.
    Sitter is identified as "Servant of A.B. Smith During Civil War".
  - Chas. A. Fairchild [Wood, E.L.], 1871/01/23 (?) (Item 3-464)
    Male figure seated 3/4 length, wearing moustache, white shirt, black bow tie, dark coat, kerchief in pocket, holding black hat in left hand, cane in right.
    Back of case: "Chas. A. Fairchild"; Inside case: "Truly you of the 20 games Euchi Chas A Fairchild Jacksonville Fla Janu 23rd 71"?
  - Mrs. James P. Harper Sr. (or Unidentified Female Harper Family Member or Friend) (Item 3-465)
    Female figure, front view, wearing black dress with white collar and cuffs, seated with her right arm resting on table, wearing ring, earrings, hair clip, curly hair.
  - Unidentified Young Female (Item 3-466)
    Young female wearing white blouse and necklace with charm, 3/4 profile, hair parted in middle and pulled back in hair-band.
    Sitter is identified as "Mother".
  - 3 Unidentified Females [Towne, W.L.] (Item 3-467)
    Three female figures, all wearing light colored gowns and bows at neck, hats, earrings, two are seated with hands on lap, one stands center leaning on backs of chairs, all front view, full length.
  - Unidentified Female [Wagoner & Russell's Bon Ton Gallery] (Item 3-468)
    Female figure, profile view, wearing hair in large curls to shoulders, long earrings, striped blouse and bow-tie, bow in hair, light colored jacket.
  - Unidentified Young Female ("Hattie") [Klein's Photographic and Ferrotype Gallery] (Item 3-469)
    Young girl seated with legs crossed, leaning on her left elbow, hand on cheek, wearing light colored dress with black horizontal lines, hair parted in middle, ribbon in hair.
    Inscription inside states that sitter is 8 year old at time of photo.
  - Unidentified Young Female (Item 3-470)
    Young girl, full length, front view, standing with her right arm resting on end of sofa, brace visible in background, wearing light colored dress with black boot and ribbon in hair, hair parted in middle and shoulder length.
  - Unidentified Young Male [Schoomaker & Burgess] (Item 3-471)
    Young boy seated with his right arm on armrest, hair parted on side, seated profile and looking off to his left, bow-tie, white shirt, dark vest and jacket.
  - Two Unidentified Males in Horse-Drawn Carriage (Item 3-472)
    2 Male figures seated in horse-drawn carriage, outdoor scene, horse in profile view, males wearing rounded hats, one holding reins, trees and bridge in background, two men standing near tree in background.
  - Unidentified Female (Item 3-473)
    Female figure, 1/4 length, front view, wearing white scalloped collar with bow at neck and brooch, black hat, earrings, choker necklace, dark dress.
  - Belle Roosevelt Hoyt (Item 3-474)
    Female figure, facing profile and looking down, wearing white crocheted shawl with black dress, white collar and cuffs, ring, flat hat with flowers and black lace, choker necklace, brooch, seated with her left arm on tasseled armrest.
  - Belle Roosevelt Hoyt [Estabrooke, Edward M.], 1876/00/00 ca. (Item 3-475)
    Female figure, front view, looking to right of camera, silhouette, wearing dark dress with patterned collar, hair in braided bun on top of head.
  - Belle Roosevelt Hoyt [Estabrooke, Edward M.], 1876/00/00 ca. (Item 3-476)
    Female figure, front view, looking to right of camera, silhouette, wearing dark dress with patterned collar, hair in braided bun on top of head, seated with her right arm resting on armrest, wearing ring.
  - Belle Roosevelt Hoyt and Miss Hiller with 3 Unidentified Males and 5 Unidentified Females (Group Portrait) [Merriam's Bon-Ton], 1869/08/19 (Item 3-477)
    10 Figures, including female holding umbrella and looking suspiciously at bearded male, male with full white beard and moustache, female with beaded brooch and straw purse, female with large oval brooch, females in white and dark dresses, female in white
  - Belle Roosevelt Hoyt and William Hoyt [Estabrooke, Edward M.] (Item 3-478)
    Female figure seated wearing light colored coat with loop hook buttons, brooch, choker necklace, hair in bun, black skirt, profile view, child seated on her lap wearing white dress with white stockings and shoes, striped belt, hair in large curl on top of
  - George B. Northrup [Alden, A. E., b. 1837] (Item 3-479)
    Male figure, front view, seated with legs crossed, wearing light colored pants with striped down side, dark jacket, black vest, white shirt, chain on vest, handkerchief in pocket, hair parted on side, bow-tie, moustache, his left arm resting on tasseled a
  - Peter Relyea with Unidentified Male and Unidentified Female (Item 3-480)
    Seated male on left wearing black jacket with pin, chain, black pants and boots, white shirt, tall black hat, white beard and dark moustache, holding cane, male standing center with white beard, tall black hat, watch on chain on vest, black jacket and bow
  - 2 Unidentified Males (Item 3-481)
    Two male figures, male on left standing wearing light colored pans, dark coat with dark vest buttoned to top, white collar, dark bow-tie, hair parted on side, ankles crossed, leaning on table with his left arm, hands joined, chain on vest, male seated on
  - Unidentified Group Portrait (6 Females, 2 Males, 1 Young Male) (Item 3-482)
    9 Figures, L-R: Female figure seated wearing black dress with small hat and flower, white patterned lining on dress, hands on lap; female figure wearing white polka dot dress with black lining at edges, buttons down front, hat; female figure wearing white
  - John Rogers [McCormick, J.L.] (Item 3-483)
    Male figure turned 3/4 to his right, wearing light gray jacket, dark bow tie, white shirt, bearded.
  - Unidentified Female Van Boskerck Family Member or Friend [Macnabb] (Item 3-484)
    Female figure, arms crossed at chest and resting on tasseled velvet cushion, wearing white earrings, dark dress with bow tie and brooch, head turned to sitter's left in profile.
    Sitter is friend or relative of landscape artist Robert W. Van Boskerck.
  - Unidentified Female Van Boskerck Family Member or Friend [Macnabb] (Item 3-485)
    Female figure, front view, wearing white earrings, dark dress with bow tie and brooch.
  - 2 Unidentified Females (2 Individual Images) (Item 3-486)
    Female figure, front vie, wearing black velvet dress with white collar, large brooch and striped bow at neck, teardrop earrings, bow on top of head, ribbon at neck, curly hair, seated with her left arm on armrest; female figure seated with her left arm on
  - Unidentified Male Chatan Family Member [Sanborn & Co.] (Item 3-487)
    Male figure wearing black jacket and white shirt, edge of bow tie visible beneath long white beard, white hair, moustache.
  - Franics P. Harper (Item 3-488)
    Male figure, full length, front view, wearing long goat and dark pants with white collar and cuffs, moustache, hair parted slightly to side, snow and trees backdrop, his right hand resting on rock fence.
  - Unidentified Male [McMillan Bros.] (Item 3-489)
    Male figure, front view, looking off to left of camera, wearing white shirt, black jacket with black vest, checked tie, goatee and moustache, hair parted on side.
    Photographer's label verso depicts cherubs/children with camera and photograph.
  - Sarah Van Santvoord, Elizabeth M. Maxwell and Helen Ashton (Item 3-490)
    Three female figures standing, female on left wearing black coat and skirt with fur lining, holding umbrella in her right hand, profile view, tall hat with flowers, female in center wearing long black dress with buttons down front, holding pocketbook in h
  - George T. Bliss (Item 3-491)
    Young boy, full length and seated in white dress with black shoes, fringes on arm of chair.
  - 2 Unidentified Males and Unidentified Female in Automobile (Item 3-492)
    Male figure and female figure seated in front of an early automobile, one male figure seated in rear, right hand of male figure in front is holding an upright lever in his right hand, auto has no top, auto is on unpaved road, landscape is hilly in rear, f
  - C.D. Reutgen (?) (Item 3-493)
    Male figure seated at table, polka dot table cloth, holding can in his right hand, wearing black jacket and vest, white shirt, cap, holding edge of table with his left hand, tree backdrop, book on table (sitter is reading), white beard.
    Inside envelope: "Dear Sirs".
  - John Ward Jr. (Item 3-494)
    Male figure, front view, full length, standing, holding sword pointing to ground, wearing uniform of the Civil War period, Grand Army of the Republic, wearing cap, bearded.
  - 2 Unidentified Males and 2 Unidentified Females (Item 3-495)
    Male figure standing wearing cap and bow-tie, long jacket with large pocket, white pants, light moustache, arms behind back, female seated on rock adjacent wearing straw hat with black dress, white collar, brooch, ring, hands folded on lap, seated male ho
  - Unidentified Female [Apllegate's Gallery], after 1891 (Item 3-496)
    Female figure with her back to the camera, standing with her right hand resting on rock, wearing hat and black dress, her left hand at her waist, scenic backdrop.
  - Charles Baxter Fellows (Item 3-497)
    Male figure, standing, front view, in uniform of the Civil War soldier (Grand Army of the Republic), 3 stripes on each sleeve, bearded, right elbow leaning on column, left hand holding cap, backdrop of a cannon and military scene.
    Sitter is brother of Mrs. Stephen Edson Paine, and that he was "Born 1838, Malta, New York. Was wounded at the storming of Ft. Gilmer and died in the service of his country-- he was in Company H of the 119th Regiment" For an account of Fellows activitie
  - Capt. John Ward Jr. and 3 Officers of the 12th Regiment N.Y.S.M. in their tent at Harper's Ferry, 1862/00/00 (Item 3-498)
    Four male figures seated at open end of tent, ten pole center, two men seated at right wearing caps, 2 men at left bareheaded, clothing and other objects handing inside tent, including bag marked "Captain Ward", hat, books, boxes.
    Original (or image taken at same time) Daguerreotype of this scene elsewhere in Cased Images File.
  - Capt. John Ward and 22 Officers of the 12th Regiment N.Y.S.M. at Harper's Ferry, 1862/00/00 (Item 3-499)
    Twenty-two male figures in soldier's uniform, Civil War period Grand Army of the Republic, standing, full length, front view, two tents in background, outdoor scene, officer in front is holding sword in both hands towards ground.
  - Capt. John Ward and Unidentified Male Soldier (Item 3-500)
    Two male figure, full length, standing, wearing uniforms of the Civil War period (Grand Army of the Republic), male on left has arms folded on stomach and is facing profile to his left looking at male on right, who is holding sword and wearing sash across
  - Fanny Donnelly (Lady Ashburton) and Mr. Sanger, 1899/06/00 (Item 3-501)
    Female figure seated wearing white blouse and checked skirt, hands clasped on lap, watch chain on blouse, hat, male seated wearing black jacket and pants, white collar, light colored hat with white band, his right arm resting on back of female's chair, oc
    Accompanying this image is a newspaper clipping and a typed note from donor that states: "The Young Woman in this tin-type was the former Frances Donnelly, now, and for some years the Lady Ashburton. It was taken in 1899, and was presented to my sister,
  - 2 Unidentified Males with Horse-Drawn Carriage (Item 3-502)